SANTIAGO DEVIA

Toronto, ON 437-256-3839 s.devia10@gmail.com

Linked-In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/santiago-devia

Post-graduate student of Software Development and Bachelor of Engineering in Electronic Engineering. Great aptitude for problem-solving, coding in different programming languages, and learning new technologies. Highly interested in web development area and data analysis, well-versed in technology, with experience in IT Support, Data Analysis and Web Applications' Development.

COMPETENCES AND SKILLS

- 1 year of experience with Python language and Machine Learning for data analysis
- 1 year experience of CSS, HTML and JavaScript for web development
- 1 year experience with Java Object Oriented Programming
- Knowledge of Microsoft Automation programs: Power Automate, PowerApps, Forms, SharePoint
- Relational database management Knowledge of SQL
- Non-relational database management Fundamental knowledge of MongoDB
- Knowledge of REACT framework and Bootstrap for Front-end development.
- Fundamental knowledge of Express and Node.js for the creation of RESTFUL API's
- Version Control Management (GIT)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Level 1 Technology Analyst - Schlumberger Colombia

- Developed applications on PowerApps for automatic production of company reports.
- Create and maintain documentation for web applications in C# and Python
- Provided remote worldwide technical support to internal customers, including issues regarding Network Connectivity, automation apps (PowerApps, Power Automate), remote connectivity, computer performance, server access, etc
- Create, resolve or escalate tickets according to urgency.

Software Developer Intern - Schlumberger Colombia

- Developed a web application using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Django framework in Python for the prediction of workload and the optimization of workers shifts' distribution.
- Creation of reports of workload during analysts' shifts on Microsoft Excel and PowerBI
- Maintained and created documentation for existing web applications of the company. Provided tutorials for managers and users.

October 2020 – December 2021

January 2020 – July 2020

Research Assistant and Tutor - Los Andes University Colombia

Tutor and research assistant for Electronic Digital Systems course

• Provide reinforcement classes for students.

Provide feedback about the software used for the course

January 2018 – December 2018

EDUCATION

Software Development and Database Management

Currently

Postgraduate Certificate - Lambton College

Electronic Engineering

2020

Bachelor's Degree - Los Andes University

STUDENT PROJECTS

Gait Recognition Algorithm: Design of an algorithm for the recognition of a person's identity through its gait silhouette sequence using MatLab programming language.

Degree Project: Characterization of craft beverage brewing system using Machine Learning techniques in Python programming Language. Grade Obtained: 100%

ONLINE COURSES

Full Stack Web Development MOOC

Hong Kong University - Coursera 2021

Machine Learning MOOC

Stanford University - Coursera 2019

VOLUNTEERING

Volunteer Professor – Colombia Crece NGO

Main professor for High School Class (Biology) for senior citizens pursing their high school diploma.

August – December 2016

Student Representative - Los Andes University

Developed and presented proposals and activities for the department's improvement and students' engagement in academic and wellbeing activities.

January – December 2019

ACHIEVEMENTS AND RECOGNITIONS

 Colombian Ministry of education: High performance at State Exam SaberPro 2019 in the Electronics Engineering field.

LANGUAGES

Bilingual English and Spanish. Intermediate French.